a time trial let's get started with day three for the month of october hi everyone i'm steve seresi
and i'm jenny skidmore thanks for joining us
this time we will be able to tell you about food that is unique to japan in english
for example sashimi
don't you call this raw fish?
生魚ではありますが、生臭いというネガティブなイメージが強くなります。
おすすめの伝え方を一緒に練習していきましょう。
It's time for your first try.
S.P.R. Training
では、僕の言う日本語を英語で表現してください。
一つ目です。
これは刺身と言います。
どうぞ。
答えを確認しましょう。
This is called sashimi.
さあ、次の文です。
これを英語でraw fishと呼ぶ人もいます。
Some people call this...
彼に言ってください。
どうぞ。
では次です。
まずこちらを英語で言ってみましょう。
食欲をそそる。
英語ではappetizing 例えば食欲をそそるフレーズならan appetizing phrase ということでan appetizing phraseを使ってこの文を言ってみよう
しかしraw fishはあまり食欲をそそるフレーズではありません
But raw fishから言ってください どうぞ
There are more and more people calling it sashimi in English as well.
Here you go.
Now, next is nori.
Let's explain it in order.
First of all,
this is called nori.
Here you go.
Now, next.
First, let's go with this in English.
海の海藻 海の海藻
これは英語で言うと sea plant
では sea plant を使ってこちらへ行ってください
海苔は海藻の一種です
これを英語で seaweed と呼ぶ人もいます
Some people call this から言ってください
では次です。
しかし、seaweedはあまり食欲をそそる単語ではありません。
But seaweed is not から言ってください。
どうぞ。
もしかすると、noriの方が食欲をそそる単語かもしれません。
英語でもノリと呼ぶ人が増えてきています。
OK. How was your first round? Did you try to say each one?
では、ここで回答例をチェックしましょう。
Listen closely.
これは刺身と言います。
This is called sashimi.
日本語の単語そのまま言うよりも、
This is called 〜。
This is called 刺身。
これを英語でraw fishと呼ぶ人もいます。
Some people call this raw fish in English.
しかし、raw fishはあまり食欲をそそるフレーズではありません。
But raw fish is not really an appetizing phrase.
英語でも、サシミと呼ぶ人が増えてきています。
何々する人が増えてきています。
を言いたいときに、
さあ、次はノリです。
まずはこちら。
これはノリと言います。
This is called nori.
Nori is a kind of sea plant.
I don't think this sea plant is necessary to introduce Japanese food culture.
Originally, hijiki, wakame, and nori are not in America, so please send a sea plant instead of seaweed.
Please send a sea plant instead of seaweed.
それのほうが食欲そそるような言葉ですから。
さあ、次です。
これを英語でseaweedと呼ぶ人もいます。
Some people call this seaweed in English.
しかし、seaweedはあまり食欲をそそる単語ではありません。
But seaweed is not really an appetizing word.
もしかすると、ノリの方が食欲をそそる単語かもしれません。
Maybe nori is a more appetizing word.
英語でもノリと呼ぶ人が増えてきています。
More and more people are calling it nori in English.
Okay, did you understand today's phrases?
それではみなさん、今学習した表現をテンポよくもう一度言ってみましょう。
We'll pick up the pace a little in round two. Here we go!
これは刺身と言います。
This is called sashimi.
これを英語でraw fishと呼ぶ人もいます。
Some people call this raw fish in English.
しかし、raw fishはあまり食欲をそそるフレーズではありません。
But raw fish is not really an appetizing phrase.
英語でもサシミと呼ぶ人が増えてきています。
More and more people are calling it sashimi in English.
これはのりと言います。
This is called nori.
のりは海藻の一種です。
これを英語でseaweedと言います。
Some people call this seaweed in English.
But seaweed is not really an appetizing word.
もしかすると、ノリの方が食欲をそそる単語かもしれません。
Maybe nori is a more appetizing word.
英語でもノリと呼ぶ人が増えてきています。
More and more people are calling it nori in English.
Okay, time's up.
Well, how was your second try?
このように説明すると、
素敵な日本の食文化、
より多くの人たちに理解してもらえると思います。
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.